<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blogs on</title><link>https://joh4nd.github.io/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Blogs on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 12:02:04 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://joh4nd.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>On the entanglement of domain interest, statistical analysis, data processing, and software engineering</title><link>https://joh4nd.github.io/blog/002-ps-cs-ds/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 12:02:04 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://joh4nd.github.io/blog/002-ps-cs-ds/</guid><description>Having interest and domain knowledge. Statistical analysis of data. Instructing computers to process data. These competencies are useful in tandem. And though their relative importance may shift, I believe the direction and the extent of this could be clearer.
10 years ago, Gary King explained that &amp;ldquo;Big data&amp;rdquo; is actually not about the data. Big data is about what you do with it. It&amp;rsquo;s about the analytics; making the data actionable.</description></item><item><title>My First Blog Post: Pixelated Pictures as Missing Data</title><link>https://joh4nd.github.io/blog/001-my-first-blog/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 10:27:19 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://joh4nd.github.io/blog/001-my-first-blog/</guid><description>Hello, World! 🌍
Finally, it&amp;rsquo;s time to make a website and blog. Let&amp;rsquo;s see where this goes. It&amp;rsquo;s mostly work-related stuff that interests me.
The left-hand-side profile picture was actually quite pixelated. But an online ai tool applied Photoshop interpolation (&amp;ldquo;made up&amp;rdquo; the finer pixels that were missing), added an art effect as online obfuscation, and removed some background. Good enough.
However, such interpolation would wrec havoc with the validity and certainty of the estimates from statistical inference or machine learning - not recommended!</description></item><item><title>war-fire insight (A Blog Post I Could Have Made)</title><link>https://joh4nd.github.io/blog/000-the-blog-i-should-have-made/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://joh4nd.github.io/blog/000-the-blog-i-should-have-made/</guid><description>Horrified by the invasion of Ukraine I came across daily war-fire insights by Solstad@theEconomist nicely summarized in this GIF. The perhaps the best polsci&amp;rsquo;s of all time have tried to infer individual behavior from geographical, ecological data, and I dare say without overwhelming success. The powerful predictors tend rather to be below the individual levels than above this level (wink: a reason to be interested in political psychology). But in the case of the war-fire model, geospatial data from satelite imagery clearly tracks the war better than individual behavior may do.</description></item></channel></rss>